When you go out to search for the best
health insurance options in the
industry, Baj Alian could have popped up
on your search. And you might have
thought to yourself, well, Bajage is
really a wellestablished brand. Why not
consider their health insurance? Well,
we'll answer that question in just a
bit. Hi folks, I'm Shashank and you're
watching Ditto Insurance and welcome to
another honest insurance review. If
you're new here, we break down complex
insurance jargon into simple terms you
can actually understand. So, hit that
subscribe button right now to stay
updated on all things insurance. And if
you're looking for expert insurance
guidance for your health or term needs,
then book a free call today with our IDI
certified adviserss to get personalized
and free support. The link is in the
description. Folks, in this video, we
break down everything that you need to
know about Bajage Health Insurance as we
discuss each plan in detail. So, stick
around till the end so you can make an
informed decision if this is the right
plan for you or not. Now, let's get into
a quick intro about this insurer. Bajach
Alian's general insurance company
limited stands as a prominent private
sector insurance provider in India.
Established as a joint venture between
Bajacher Limited and Aliance SE, the
company offers a wide range of insurance
products including motor, health,
travel, home and commercial insurance.
But soon Alian's SE will be selling
their stake to Bajage and leaving the
joint venture soon. Now, Bajage Health
Insurance operates in over thousand
towns and cities across India, supported
by a robust distribution network of
approximately 50,000 agents and 9,000
motor dealer partners and 130 bank
partners. When comparing Bajalian's
health insurance with top players in the
market, we can observe several key
metrics. Bajalian maintains an
impressive CSR of 95% average which is
higher than many competitors like Star
Health at 83%, Care Health at 90 and
Nabupa at 91%. Baj Al Jalian also offers
access to 12,000 plus network hospitals
which is substantial. Bajalian has only
three complaints per 10,000 claims on an
average. Significantly, this is lower
than Star Health's 46, Care Health at 36
and Newa at 43. The company also
maintains a healthy 81% average ICR
which is comparable to Star Health at
73%, HDFCO at 86%. With 24 plus years of
experience, this insurer has one of the
longest track records in the industry,
matched only by HDFC. With the intro and
metrics out of the way, it's time that
we get into the six plans that they
offer. Starting off with the first plan,
HealthGuard Plan. This is their flagship
plan available in silver, gold, and
platinum variants. Now, talking about
the basic features, no default
co-ayment, though zonal co-pay applies
if treatment is availed in a higher
premium zone. This plan has room limits
and they vary by the plan. Silver plan
limits to 1% of some insured per day
while gold and platinum plans offer
single private AC rooms for some insured
of three to seven and a half lakh rupees
and any room category for some insured
of 10 lak rupees and above. Disease wise
sub limits also apply for catact and
beriatric surgeries. Pre and post
hospitalization charges are covered for
60 days and 90 days respectively.
Daycare procedures and I treatments are
covered up to some insured. Free annual
health checkups with varying limits
based on the variant. Restoration
benefit is applicable once during a
policy year only for different ailments
and upon complete exhaustion of the base
I'm in short. Now a quick look into
special features. It has a cumulative
bonus varying by plan. Silver and gold
plans offer 10% per year up to 100%
while the platinum plan offers 50% for
the first 2 years and 10% for the next 5
years up to 150%. The platinum variant
includes a recharge benefit increasing
some insured by 20% and maximum up to
only five lakh rupees if claim amount
exceeds policy coverage. Golden platinum
plans also offer maternity benefits
after a long 72 months waiting period
and newborn care as well. While the plan
does provide a decent coverage
structure, the premium pricing may not
be the most competitive in the market.
Wellness benefits include discounts on
renewal premiums for maintaining good
health. Coming to add-ons, it has air
ambulance coverage which is optional for
some insured of 5 lakh rupees and above
with coverage limits from 5 to 50 lakh
rupees depending on some insurance
chosen. Voluntary aggregate deductible
is also available with the limit options
of 50,000, 1 lakh, 2 lakh or three lakh
rupees. So what's the verdict here? This
is a decent basic plan with good
cumulative bonus in the platinum variant
up to 150%. But there are room rent
limits and disease-wise sublims because
of which we don't recommend this plan at
DTO. Now the second plan is the health
infinity plan which is rather a simple
plan offering unlimited sum in short
based on room rent. You heard it right
based on room rent. Now let's look at
the basic features. Copay applies if a
policy holder chooses a room above their
plan limit. Room rent limits range from
3,000 to 50,000 rupees per day. There is
no disease-wise sub limit. Pre and post
hospitalization charges are covered for
60 and 90 days respectively. Daycare
procedures covered up to some insured.
Aish treatments though are not covered
and free health checkups are available
at the end of every three policy years.
There is no restoration benefit, no
cumulative bonus which makes it a less
attractive one and it's got a road
ambulance coverage up to 5,000 rupees
per hospitalization. Looking at certain
special features, the plan offers
unlimited summon shot based on chosen
daily room rent limits providing
extensive coverage without maximum
limits. So what is the verdict here? The
plan lacks essential features as you see
like the restoration benefit and
cumulative bonus and that is why this is
not at all recommended. Next up is a
super topper plan designed to provide
additional coverage beyond an existing
health policy and they've called it
extra care plus policy. Looking at its
basic features, it has no co-ayment, no
room rent limits, no deceases by
sublimmits, pre and post covered for 60
and 90 days respectively. Daycare
procedures and IU treatments are covered
up to some insured but there is no free
annual health checkups, no restoration
benefit, no cumulative bonus and it
boasts of a shorter waiting period that
is 30 days initial waiting period, 12
months for specific conditions and 12
months for PDS. Some special features
are the pre-existing diseases waiting
period of it being only 12 months which
is shorter than most super top-up plans
that typically require 24 to 36 months.
Maternity expenses are covered over and
above the deductible threshold after a
12 month waiting period. So what is the
verdict? Well, there isn't much to say
about the super topup other than this
being a decent option for someone who's
seeking additional coverage beyond their
base plan. Well, we've made an extensive
video about the best super top-up plans.
I'll link it in the description below.
Do check it out. Now folks, before we
head to the next plan, let me tell you
that Titto is your insurance buddy. We
just don't help you purchase a policy.
But let's say if you want to compare two
plans or if you want to understand how
insurance works, we can do that for you.
Well, we help you with health and term
insurance advice. And all our services
are free of cost to you. So, how do you
avail our services? Just head to the
link in the description, book your free
call and choose the slot that you want
and our advisers will contact you and
you can have a free 30-inute call with
them and decide if you want to get the
policy or not. There is no pushy
salesperson. There is no spam and again
all our services are completely free.
Now back to the video. Next up is the my
healthcare plan which is a model policy
offering extensive customization
options. Taking a quick look at the
basic policy features, this has no
co-ayment. This has a room rent limit
based on some insured that is single
private room for some insured of 3 to 10
lakh rupees and any room for some
insured about 10 lakh rupees. Now
disease- wise sub limits apply on catact
for lower some insured options that is
below 10 lakh rupees. They have a
standard pre and post hospitalization
charges covered for up to 60 and 90 days
respectively. Daycare procedures, IU
treatments and doicillary expenses are
also covered up until summon shot. Free
annual health checkups available once
every policy year. Restoration benefit
varies that is once for some insured
less than five lakh rupees unlimited for
some insured of five lakh rupees and
above. The cumulative bonus structure is
somewhat like this 25% peranom up to
100% for some insured of 3 to four lakh
rupees 50% peranom up to 100% for some
insured of 5 lakh rupees and above. Now
let's take a quick look at special
features. This has built-in consumables
coverage. There is also maternity
coverage with a 3-year waiting period
reducible by 1 year if premium is paid
for 3 years altogether with coverage
ranging from 50,000 rupees to 1 lak
rupees based on the summon shot. It also
has a newborn baby cover ranging from 1
lakh to 15 lak rupees based on summon
shot. There's also OPD coverage
including teleconultations in clinic
consultations and doctor prescribed
tests. There is also home nursing cover
for up to 10 weeks upon doctor's
prescription. There's also coverage for
prescribed external medical aids like
braces, canes, and wheelchairs. There's
also a renewal premium waiver benefit if
the proposer dies during the policy
period due to accidental injury or
illness. This plan has some interesting
add-ons. One is a loss of income cover
providing weekly payments for
hospitalizations lasting at least 72
consecutive hours. It also has major
illness and accident multiplier that
doubles the sum in short for specified
critical illnesses or injuries. There is
also international cover for emergency
care only covering expenses incurred
outside India with a mandatory 10%
co-ayment. So after all this what is the
verdict? This is one of Bajad's better
offering with unlimited restoration for
higher summons short options and strong
cumulative bonus. Additional benefits
like OPD cover and built-in consumables
make it worth considering. Now the next
plan is the healthcare supreme which is
a comprehensive health insurance policy
with three variants vital smart and
ultim. A quick look at the basic
features it has no co-ayment no room
rent limits no disease wise sub limits
standard pre and post hospitalization
charges covered for up to 60 and 90 days
respectively. Daycare procedures and
nish treatments covered up to some
insured. Free annual health checkups are
available and the restoration benefit of
100% is available only once a year upon
complete exhaustion of base cover and
only for different illnesses. There's
also cumulative bonus of 10% per year up
to a maximum of 50% upon no claims. The
waiting period is standard 30 days
initial 12 to 24 months for specified
conditions and 24 months for PDS. Now
some special features include maternity
cover including newborn coverage ranging
from 25,000 to 1 lak depending on the
variant and some in short chosen. It
also has OPD cover ranging from 2,500 to
25,000 rupees including specialist
consultation, prescribed investigations,
medicines, dental procedures and
psychiatric consultations.
Physiootherapy on OPD basis is also
covered with coverage ranging from 5,000
to 50,000 rupees. There is also recovery
benefit providing a one-time lumpsum
payment if hospitalized for more than
seven consecutive days. This is a
comprehensive plan with good OPD and
maternity coverage, but the restoration
and cumulative bonus benefits are
limited. So, what do we think about this
plan? This is a comprehensive plan with
good OPD and maternity coverage, but the
restoration and cumulative bonus
benefits are sort of limited. Somewhat
competitive, but falls short compared to
top plans from other insurers. Finally,
the last plan is Baj Alan Silver Health,
which is designed for individual aged 46
and above with some insured options
ranging from 50,000 to 10 lakh rupees.
Now, the basic features include 10%
co-ayment on each admissible claim. The
room rent is limited to a single private
AC room. Deceased sub limits are also
applicable on catacts and domicillary
treatments. Pre and post hospitalization
charges are covered for 30 and 60 days
respectively, which is quite quite less.
Daycare procedures and eye treatments
covered up to some short. Domicillary
expenses covered up to 10% of some
insured. Now there is free annual health
checkups available only once every two
years. There is no restoration benefit
and cumulative bonus of 10% per year up
to a maximum of 100% upon no claims. The
waiting period is 30 days for initial 12
to 24 months for specified conditions
and only 12 months for PEDs. Needless to
say, its standout feature is a lower
waiting period of just 12 months for
PEDs compared to industry standard of 24
to 36 months. It's got a room rent
modifier add-on that changes the room
rent restriction from single private
room to 1% of sum insured maximum up to
7,500 rupees per day. So finally folks
what is the verdict on Bajage health
insurance as a whole. Now Bajage Alian
demonstrates strong performance metrics
including a high CSR and significant
business volumes along with impressively
low complaint rates. However, upon
reviewing their insurance plans, it
becomes quite evident that new
Pajalyan's health insurance plan options
lack truly comprehensive coverage
compared to competitors. Among the
available plans, only the healthcare
supreme is somewhat competitive with
offerings like Care Supreme and Active 1
Max. However, even this plan falls short
in terms of providing comprehensive
bonus and restoration benefits.
Additionally, their premiums tend to be
relatively high considering the limited
features provided. So before making a
decision on Bajalian's health insurance,
review findings, speak with our experts
at Ditto. Our insurance advisors can
help you navigate the complex world of
health insurance and find the right plan
that suits your specific needs and
budget. Book your free consultation
today with the link in the description
and make an informed decision about
Bajalian's health insurance or other
available options in the market. So
that's it for today folks. If you found
this video helpful, then please drop a
like and subscribe to DTO insurance if
you haven't already. I'll see you in the
next one. Until then, happy insurance
hunting.